Explosive high adventure!
Force 10 from Navarone is a drama, adventure, war film directed by Guy Hamilton.
World War II, 1943.
Mallory and Miller, the heroes who destroyed the guns of Navarone, are
sent to Yugoslavia in search of a ghost from the past.
Mallory, played by Robert Shaw.
Barnsby, played by Harrison Ford.
Maritza, played by Barbara Bach.
Miller, played by Edward Fox.
Lescovar, played by Franco Nero.
Weaver, played by Carl Weathers.
Force 10 from Navarone is a 1978 action war film loosely based on
Alistair MacLean's 1968 novel of the same name.
It is a sequel to the 1961 film The Guns of Navarone.
The parts of Mallory and Miller are played by Robert Shaw (who died before the film was released), and
Edward Fox, succeeding in the roles originally portrayed by Gregory Peck and David Niven.
It was directed by Guy Hamilton and also stars Harrison Ford, Carl Weathers, Barbara Bach,
Franco Nero (in a role previously played by Tutte Lemkow), and Richard Kiel.
The film gets its title from the Alistair MacLean book of the same name, but bears so little resemblance to
the novel that MacLean loosely adapted part of the screenplay into his 1982 book Partisans.
The film explores themes of guerrilla warfare, based on novel
or book, yugoslavia, world war ii, sequel.
The tone is emotional.